ALEX CARTER

Oracle certified Full stack Developer

📞 +1-234-253-6506 @ danette.eastwood@gmail.com & github.io/danette.east 🗣 San Fransisco, CA

SUMMARY

Full Stack Developer with over 10 years of experience in Java/JS, Angular, Vue, React, Python, NumPy, SciPy, Scikit-learn. Led development of \$500K research project which was deemed a "gold standard" by the client. Increased client's revenue 2-fold after fine-tuning Al/ML-based algorithms. Well-acquainted with HR methodologies.

EDUCATION

M.S. in Computer Science

Stanford Unversity

GPA 3.9 / 4.0

EXPERIENCE

Senior Full stack Developer

Boyle

苗 2018 - Present 👂 San Fransisco, CA

Boyle is an international Technology and Management Consulting Group with a rapid pace development and innovative solutions for demanding projects. I work as a full-stack developer here, responsible for building, deploying and maintaining internal web applications.

- · Hired, trained and leading an Agile team of 7 full-stack developers
- · Developed indexed database architecture using SQL procedures and triggers for 10 different applications
- Worked with Core Java to develop automated solutions to include web interfaces using HTML, CSS, JavaScript and Web services
- Worked with a committee of 6 members to organise fun-activities for the employees

Full Stack Developer

Lauzon

苗 2013 - 2018 👂 San Fransisco, CA

Lauzon is a universal digital loyalty program that offers unique and fun rewards at the places you love.

- Hired, trained and lead Agile team of 7 full-stack developers
- Simultaneously created & maintained scheduled jobs in SQL Server for space maintenance and daily backups of system and user databases for 10 clients
- Increased company revenue by 30% within 2 months after developing and implementing business logic for over 20 features
- Designed and Developed UI design for over 15 clients using CSS, HTML, ASP.NET, Vue, and React; websites scoring over 85 on Lighthouse

Solution Architect

Keeling Group

= 2010 - 2013 Palo Alto, CA

Keeling Group is a leading Digital Product Studio in California, helping companies to thrive on mobile apps, the web, VR/AR and IoT.

- · Shortened project timeline by 14 months for company's largest customer by managing relationship with 3rd party vendors, saving over \$800K
- Led development of \$500K research project which was deemed a "gold standard" by the client
- Fine-tuned and developed AI/ML-based algorithms based on the results with Scikit-learn, increasing revenue 2-fold
- Performed Web Scraping over a catalog of 100K+ school supply products using mainly NodeJS and MongoDB; completed in 1 month

SKILLS

Client-Side

HTML **CSS** JS **Angular** Redux **TypeScript** React Vue **Backbone Bootstrap**

Server-side

HTTP/2

Python NumPy SciPy Scikit-learn Eli5 Keras **TensorFlow MySQL NodeJS** Redis **AWS** MongoDB Spark

Development & Operations

JUnit NUnit PyUnit TestCafe Mocha Scrum Agile Jest **GIT Azure DevOps**

PROJECTS

OpenFlow based Firewall

https://github.com/danette.east/OpenFlow-Firewall OpenFlow protocol-based proactive Firewall in Python and NodeJS.

- · Configured static rules using MD-SAL
- Engineered proactive rule evaluation system at OSI layer 7 using POX controller
- · Provided flexibility to configure rule using centralised NodeJS based GUI

STRENGTHS

Team Leadership

Introduction to Leadership course by Harvard

Communication

Attended a Communication course at **Stanford**.

Powered by Enhancy